Register of the Morris Childs papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Morris Childs papers
1924-1995
98069
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes, 35 microfilm reels (4.3 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, notes, speeches and writings, and interview transcripts relating to Federal Bureau of Investigation surveillance of the Communist Party, and the relationship between the Communist Party of the United States and the Soviet communist party and government. Includes some papers of John Barron used as research material for his book Operation Solo: The FBI's Man in the Kremlin (Washington, D.C., 1996). Hard-copy material also available on microfilm (2 reels).
Childs, Morris, 1902-1991.
Barron, John, 1930-2005.
Location of Original Materials
J. Edgar Hoover Foundation (in part).
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1998.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Hard-copy material also available on microfilm (2 reels).
Related Collections
John Barron papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1902 June 10 Born Moishe Chilovsky, Kiev, Ukraine
1911 Arrived in the United States Ellis Island
1921 Joined the United Communist Party of America
1929-1932 Received training at the International Lenin School in Moscow
1933-1938 Functionary of the Communist Party, member of the Central Committee
1936 Ran for U.S. Congress in Illinois
1946-1947 Editor, Daily Worker
1954-1982 Cooperated with FBI agents in Operation SOLO
1987 Awarded the Presidential Medal of Freedom for Intelligence
1991 June 5 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection includes mainly papers of Morris Childs (1902-1991), a prominent member of the Communist Party USA (CPUSA). From 1954 to 1982, Morris Childs, along with his brother Jack Childs and wife Eva Childs, participated in an operation which was conducted by the FBI, and later named SOLO.
Within Operation SOLO the FBI supported a clandestine communication system designed and built by the Soviet KGB (Committee for State Security). Through this system the FBI regularly received messages from the Kremlin and, in the name of Jack or Morris, sent back information the United States wanted the Soviets to get. The FBI also handled millions of dollars smuggled from the Soviet Union to New York, either by Jack or Morris or by KGB agents, for the CPUSA. Morris Childs made fifty-seven trips (called by the FBI "missions") to the Soviet Union and other countries of the socialist camp. He often accompanied Gus Hall, General Secretary of the CPUSA; sometimes he traveled alone or with his wife. Morris had conferences with party leaders in the countries he visited and was shown confidential and secret documents. He took almost verbatim records of what he had heard or seen, and the notes were later handed over to FBI agents. These notes, both holograph and typescript (slightly edited), are included in the collection in the Morris Childs File. They give a most vivid impression of the position taken by communist leaders on various international issues. The collection also includes Morris Childs's notebooks with brief notes about the places he visited and people he met, as well as his interview transcript prepared by FBI agents.
Microfilm of Morris Childs materials on loan from the J. Edgar Hoover Foundation include correspondence, reports, and notes relating to Federal Bureau of Investigation surveillance of the Communist Party, and the relationship between the Communist Party of the United States and the Soviet communist party and government. The original papers are held by the J. Edgar Hoover Foundation. A transfer table indicating corresponding folder and microfilm reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
Communism--United States.; Communist Party of the United States of America.; Internal security--United States.; Kommunisticheskai͡a partii͡a Sovetskogo Soi͡uza.; United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation.; Communism--Soviet Union.
- Morris Childs File, 1938-1989 (Boxes 1-2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, interview transcript, memorandum, notes, notebooks, radio and other addresses, essays, and miscellaneous items, arranged alphabetically by physical form, relating to the activities of Morris Childs, in particular to his trips to the Soviet Union and other countries.
  Also available on microfilm (Reels 34-35 -- folders in Box 1 are on Reel 34, folders in Box 2 are on Reel 35).
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - Unidentified, 1965-1989 (Box-folder 1: 1)
      - Brezhnev, Leonid I. (draft), undated (Box-folder 1: 2)
      - Chicago Sun, 1945 (Box-folder 1: 3)
      - Corrick, Donald W., 1947 (Box-folder 1: 4)
      - Dennis, Eugene (Gene), 1945 (Box-folder 1: 5)
      - Hall, Gus, undated (Box-folder 1: 6)
      - Krumbein, Charles, 1945 (Box-folder 1: 7)
      - Lee, Davis C., 1945 (Box-folder 1: 8)
      - Ryle, Joe (Box-folder 1: 9)
    - Clandestine, undated (Box-folder 1: 10)
      With Soviet counterparts. Includes decoding tables.
  - Interview transcript by FBI agents Charles Knox and James Millburn, 1986 November
    - Tape nos. 3-6 (Box-folder 1: 11)
    - Tape nos. 7-9 and 12 (Box-folder 1: 12)
    - Tape no. 10 (Box-folder 1: 13)
      Original holograph transcript with name index.
    - Tape nos. 13-14 (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - Tape nos. 14 (side 3) and 17 (Box-folder 1: 15)
    - Tape nos. 19-21 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Memorandum, 1965 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Notebooks, 1966 and 1969
    - Undated (Box-folder 1: 18)
    - 1966 August-September (Box-folder 1: 19)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Notes (holograph and typescript), 1962-1974
    - Meetings with the representatives of communist parties (Canada, Cuba, Cyprus, Portugal, Vietnam, Soviet Union) and analyses of the situation in Indonesia, Middle East, Soviet assistance to national liberation movements, undated (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - Soviet-Chinese relations, undated (Box-folder 2: 2)
    - Soviet-Chinese relations, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - Report by Gus Hall, 23rd Congress of the KPSS, 1966 January-April (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - Trip with Gus Hall to the USSR, Bulgaria, Poland, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, and East Germany, 1966 August-September (Box-folder 2: 5)
    - Trips to Mongolia, Romania, Czechoslovakia; the National Convention of the CPUSA, 1966 October-December (Box-folder 2: 6)
    - Meetings with leaders of the communist parties of Venezuela, the Soviet Union, East Germany, Argentina, South Africa, Israel, Canada, and Syria, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 2: 7)
    - Meetings with leaders of the communist parties of North Vietnam and the Soviet Union, 1971 (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - Meetings with the KPSS leaders, 1972 and 1974 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Speeches and writings, 1938-1945
    - "The Farmer Labor Party United Front USA,", undated (Box-folder 2: 10)
    - "Philosophic Nihilism Serves Reaction,", undated (Box-folder 2: 11)
    - Radio and other addresses, 1938 August-October (Box-folder 2: 12)
    - Discussion speech at the Plenary Meeting of the National Committee of the CPUSA, 1945 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Miscellany, 1967 and 1976 (Box-folder 2: 14)
    Includes business cards, guest passes, concert program, and invitation cards, mainly relating to the trips to the Soviet Union (mostly in Russian).
- Eva Childs File, 1995, undated (Box 2)
  Memoirs and supplement to last will and testament of Eva Childs, wife of Morris Childs.
  Also available on microfilm (Reel 35).
  - Memoirs, holograph and typescript, undated (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - "Separate writing to last will and testament," typescript, 1995 (Box-folder 2: 16)
- Jack Childs File, 1964 (Box 2)
  Biographical notes and correspondence of Jack Childs, brother of Morris Childs, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Biographical notes, undated (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box-folder 2: 18)
- Photographs, 1977, undated (Box-folder 2: 19)
- Microfilm of Materials from the J. Edgar Hoover Foundation, 1924-1988 (Reels 1-33)
  Correspondence, reports, and notes relating to Federal Bureau of Investigation surveillance of the Communist Party, and the relationship between the Communist Party of the United States and the Soviet communist party and government. The original papers are held by the J. Edgar Hoover Foundation. A transfer table indicating corresponding folder and microfilm reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
  - Communist Party of the United States of America file, 1937-1979
    Bulletins, correspondence, course materials, financial records, minutes, pamphlets, reports, serial issues, and other printed matter.
    - Party meetings file, 1945-1979
      - Folder 1. 16th National Convention, 1957 (Reel 1)
      - Folder 2. 17th National Convention, 1959 (Reel 1)
      - Folders 3-4. 18th National Convention, 1966 (Reel 1)
      - Folder 5. 19th National Convention, 1969 (Reel 1)
      - Folder 6. 20th National Convention, 1972 (Reel 1)
      - Folder 7. 21st National Convention, 1975 (Reel 1)
      - Folder 8. 22nd National Convention, 1979 (Reel 2)
      - Folder 9. Meeting of 81 communist parties, 1961 (Reel 2)
      - National Committee meetings
        - Folder 10. 1945 (Reel 2)
        - Folder 11. 1956 (Reel 2)
      - Folder 12. Central Executive Committee meeting, 1970 (Reel 2)
      - Folder 13. Central Committee meetings, 1972-1973 (Reel 2)
      - Folder 14. Miscellaneous records and publications, 1956-1973 (Reel 3)
      - Folders 15-16. Political Committee meetings, 1970-1977 (Reel 3)
      - Folder 17. Preparatory Committee meetings, 1968-1971 (Reel 3)
      - Folder 18. National Youth Commission meeting, 1946 (Reel 3)
      - Folder 19. Negro Commission meeting, 1967 (Reel 3)
    - State parties file, 1937-1966
      - Folder 20. California, 1947-1966 (Reel 3)
      - Illinois
        - General
          - Folder 21. 1945-1959 (Reel 3)
          - Folder 22. 1960-1964 (Reel 3)
        - Folders 23-24. Chicago Workers School, 1937-1950 (Reel 4)
        - Folder 25. Labor Committee, 1946-1947 (Reel 4)
        - Folder 26. Legislative Bureau, 1939 (Reel 4)
      - Folder 27. Kansas, 1965 (Reel 4)
      - New York
        - Folder 28. 1947-1954 (Reel 4)
        - Folder 29. 1956-1966 (Reel 5)
      - Folder 30. Oregon, undated (Reel 5)
    - Folders 31-33. Education file, 1944-1967 (Reel 5)
      Course materials and printed matter used in political education classes.
    - Folder 34. Financial records, 1960-1961 (Reel 5)
    - Folder 35. Correspondence, 1961-1976 (Reel 6)
      Includes correspondence conducted by Gus Hall with various communist leaders.
    - Miscellany
      Includes handwritten notes by Morris Childs, as well as reports, serial issues, and other printed matter.
      - Folders 36-41. Unsorted material (Reel 6)
      - Folder 42. 1955 (Reel 6)
      - Folder 43. 1959 (Reel 6)
      - Folders 44-45. 1960s (Reels 6-7)
      - Folder 46. 1960-1961 (Reel 7)
      - Folders 47-48. 1965 (Reel 7)
      - Folder 49. 1973-1974 (Reel 7)
  - Country file, 1936-1976
    Correspondence, notes, pamphlets, photographs, and serial issues, largely relating to individual communist parties.
    - Folder 50. Austria, 1937 (Reel 7)
    - Folder 51. Burma, 1961 (Reel 7)
    - Canada
      - Folder 52. 1950s-1960 (Reel 7)
      - Folder 53. 1951-1965 (Reel 7)
    - Folder 54. Ceylon, 1960 (Reel 7)
    - Folder 55. Chile, 1958-1965 (Reel 8)
    - Czechoslovakia
      - Folder 56. 1962 (Reel 8)
      - Folder 57. 1968-1971 (Reel 8)
    - Folder 58. Dominican Republic, 1965 (Reel 8)
    - Folder 59. Ecuador, circa 1962 (Reel 8)
    - Folder 60. Finland, 1939 (Reel 8)
    - France
      - Folder 61. 1936-1961 (Reel 8)
      - Folder 62. 1976 (Reel 8)
    - Folder 63. German Democratic Republic, 1974 (Reel 8)
    - Folder 64. Ghana, 1965 (Reel 8)
    - Folder 65. Guatemala, 1954 (Reel 8)
    - Folder 66. Guyana, 1960s (Reel 8)
    - Folder 67. Hong Kong, 1966 (Reel 8)
    - Folder 68. Iraq, 1959 (Reel 8)
    - Folder 69. Israel, 1946-1966 (Reel 8)
    - Folder 70. Italy, 1976 (Reel 9)
    - Folder 71. Mexico, 1944-1959 (Reel 9)
    - Folder 72. North Vietnam, 1969 (Reel 9)
    - Folder 73. Philippines, 1971 (Reel 9)
    - Folder 74. Poland, 1973 (Reel 9)
    - Folder 75. Puerto Rico, 1976 (Reel 9)
    - Folder 76. Romania, 1976 (Reel 9)
    - Folder 77. South Vietnam and Laos, 1971 (Reel 9)
    - Folder 78. Spain, 1936 (Reel 9)
    - Folder 79. Venezuela, 1966 (Reel 9)
    - Folders 80-81. Miscellaneous unsorted material (Reel 9)
  - Alphabetical file, 1937-1979
    Correspondence, notes, photographs, and printed material, organized by name of individual, organization, or subject.
    - Folder 82. Albertson case, 1956 (Reel 9)
    - Folder 83. American Institute for Marxist Studies, 1965-1977 (Reel 10)
    - Folder 84. Blair, Fred and Mary, 1950-1964 (Reel 10)
    - Folder 85. Browder, Earl, 1938-1946 (Reel 10)
    - Folder 86. Burlak, Anne, 1958 (Reel 10)
    - Folder 87. Central Intelligence Agency, 1964 (Reel 10)
    - Folder 88. Childs, Eva, 1960-1961 (Reel 10)
    - Folders 89-91. Childs, Morris, 1944-1968 (Reel 10)
    - Folder 92. China, 1962-1966 (Reel 10)
    - Folder 93. Citizens Committee for Constitutional Rights, 1961-1966 (Reel 10)
    - Folder 94. Civil Rights Congress of Illinois, 1955 (Reel 10)
    - Folder 95. Control Commission, 1958-1961 (Reel 10)
    - Folder 96. Davis, Angela, 1971 (Reel 10)
    - Folder 97. Dennis, Eugene, 1945-1961 (Reel 10)
    - Folders 98-99. Dennis, Peggy, 1960s-1975 (Reel 11)
    - Folder 100. Development of the working class, undated (Reel 11)
    - Folder 101. Educational materials, 1960-1965 (Reel 11)
    - Folders 102-103. Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley, 1959-1964 (Reel 11)
    - Folder 104-105. Foreign ministers conference, 1957 (Reels 11-12)
    - Folder 106. Foster, William Z., 1947 (Reel 12)
    - Folder 107. Gates, John, undated (Reel 12)
    - Folder 108. German Democratic Republic, undated (Reel 12)
    - Folder 109. Goddard College, 1972 (Reel 12)
    - Folder 110. Goldway, Inc., 1966 (Reel 12)
    - Folder 111. Green, Gil, 1945 (Reel 12)
    - Folder 112. Gromyko, Andrei, undated (Reel 12)
    - Folders 113-117. Hall, Gus, 1964-1979 (Reel 12)
    - Folder 118. International Publishers, 1963 (Reel 12)
    - Folder 119. Johnson, Beatrice, undated (Reel 12)
    - Folder 120. Kling, Jack, 1961-1964 (Reel 12)
    - Folder 121. Kling, Susan, 1968-1969 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 122. Krchmarek, Anthony, 1957 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 123. Ku Klux Klan, 1965 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 124. Kushner, Sam, undated (Reel 13)
    - Folder 125. Lannon, Albert and Elva, 1963 (Reel 13)
    - Folders 126-127. Lightfoot, Claude, 1946-1966 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 128. Lincoln Brigade, 1937-1952 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 129. Lumer, Hyman, 1961 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 130. McCarran Internal Security Act, 1965-1966 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 131. Maysonet, Jorge W., 1960 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 132. Midwest Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born, undated (Reel 13)
    - Folder 133. Miller, Versta, 1979 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 134. Modern Book Store, 1966 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 135. Moore, James, undated (Reel 13)
    - Folder 136. Muslims, 1964-1965 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 137. National Committee to Combat Nazism, 1962-1966 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 138. National Executive Committee, 1968 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 139. New Century Publishers, 1946-1954 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 140. Newspaper clippings, 1960-1961 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 141. Nixon, Richard, 1971 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 142. Peace and Socialism in Europe, undated (Reel 13)
    - Folder 143. Ponomarev, B. N., 1977 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 144. Preparatory Committee, 1968 (Reel 13)
    - Folder 145. Print shop, undated (Reel 14)
    - Folder 146. Privacy laws, 1977 (Reel 14)
    - Folder 147. Progressive Labor Party, undated (Reel 14)
    - Folder 148. "Reo Able Cox,", undated (Reel 14)
    - Folder 149. Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel, 1952-1963 (Reel 14)
    - Folder 150. Shevliagin, D., 1957-1958 (Reel 14)
    - Folder 151. Shoulders, John, 1964 (Reel 14)
    - Folder 152. Socialist report, undated (Reel 14)
    - Folder 153. Students for a Democratic Society (S.D.S.), 1966 (Reel 14)
    - Folder 154. Suslov, Mikhail, 1977 (Reel 14)
    - Folder 155. Teachers of the World, 1956 (Reel 14)
    - Folder 156. Thompson, Robert, 1947-1965 (Reel 14)
    - Folder 157. Thompson, Robert Glen, 1965 (Reel 14)
    - Folder 158. Veterans for Peace in Vietnam, 1965-1966 (Reel 14)
    - Folder 159. Weinstone, William, undated (Reel 14)
    - Folder 160. West, James, undated (Reel 14)
    - Folder 161. Williamson, John, 1937-1958 (Reel 14)
    - Folder 162. Winston, Henry, 1963 (Reel 14)
    - Folder 163. Winters, Carl and Helen, 1963 (Reel 14)
    - Folder 164. Women's International Democratic Federation, 1964 (Reel 14)
    - Folder 165. Young Workers Liberation League, 1979 (Reel 14)
  - Communist Party of the Soviet Union file, 1956-1976
    Articles, directives, notes, reports, resolutions, serial issues, speeches, and printed matter, largely relating to congresses of the CPSU.
    - Folder 166. 20th Party Congress, 1956 (Reel 14)
    - Folders 167-170. 21st Party Congress, 1959 (Reel 15)
    - Folder 171. 22nd Party Congress, 1961 (Reel 15)
    - Folders 172-175. 23rd Party Congress, 1966 (Reels 15-16)
    - Folders 176-177. 24th Party Congress, 1971 (Reel 16)
    - Folder 178. 25th Party Congress, 1976 (Reel 16)
  - Soviet publications file, 1937-1988
    - Daily Review
      Translations from the Soviet press published by the Soviet Information Bureau and the Novosti Press Agency.
      - Folders 179-180. 1959 (Reel 16)
      - Folder 181. 1964-1966 (Reel 16)
      - Folder 182. 1968-1969 (Reel 17)
      - Folder 183. 1975-1980 (Reel 17)
    - Pravda
      - Folder 184. 1961-1975 (Reel 17)
      - Folder 185. 1977 (Reel 17)
    - Folder 186. Miscellaneous publications, 1937-1977 (Reel 17)
    - Folder 187. Miscellaneous articles from the Soviet press, 1960-1988 (Reel 18)
    - Folder 188. Miscellaneous concert and conference programs from the Soviet Union, 1960-1972 (Reel 18)
  - Folder 189. Articles about Jews in the Soviet Union and elsewhere, 1958-1966 (Reel 18)
  - Folder 190. Serial issues from Panama and the German Democratic Republic, 1974-1975 (Reel 18)
  - Folder 191. Bibliography of works largely relating to the history of the Soviet Union, undated (Reel 18)
  - Hungary file, 1962-1977
    - 8th Congress of the Hungarian Socialist Workers' Party, 1962
      - Folders 192-194. Reports, resolutions, and speeches (Reel 18)
      - Folder 195. Serial issues (Reel 18)
    - Folders 196-199. Meetings of the Working Group and the Preparatory Committee of the International Conference of Communist and Workers' Parties, Budapest, Hungary, 1968 (Reel 19)
      Communiqués, reports, resolutions, speeches, and other records.
    - Folder 200. Memorandum and miscellaneous publications, 1968-1977 (Reel 19)
  - Photographs, 1940s-1970s
    - Folder 201. 10 prints depicting Earl Browder, Gus Hall, and other American communists, undated (Reel 19)
    - Folder 202. 25 prints depicting Gus Hall, Morris Childs, Leonid Brezhnev, and others in Hungary, Poland, and the Soviet Union, undated (Reel 19)
    - Folder 203. 5 prints depicting Gus Hall and others, 1977 (Reel 19)
    - Folder 204. 24 prints depicting Henry Winston, Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Nikita Khrushchev, and others, circa 1960s (Reel 19)
    - Folder 205. 28 prints depicting Gus Hall, Elizabeth Gurley Flynn and Henry Winston meeting with Leonid Brezhnev and other Communist leaders, taken during visits to the Soviet Union, Poland, and the German Democratic Republic, circa 1960s-1970s (Reel 19)
    - Folder 206. 28 miscellaneous prints, largely depicting American Communist leaders, undated (Reel 19)
      Includes 1 print depicting Vladimir Lenin, 1 print depicting Republican soldiers (possibly from the International Brigades) in the Spanish Civil War, and 4 prints depicting the ruined palace of Catherine the Great.
    - Folder 207. 61 prints depicting Earl Browder, Gus Hall, Gus Polites, Leonid Brezhnev, and others, 1940s-1970s (Reel 20)
      Includes 2 prints depicting a Soviet supersonic airliner.
    - Folder 208. 1 album containing 41 prints and 21 negatives depicting Gus Hall, Morris Childs, and others on a trip to Bulgaria, circa 1970s (Reel 20)
    - Folder 209. 1 album containing 76 prints depicting Gus Hall during visits to the Soviet Union, circa 1970s (Reel 20)
    - Folder 210. 1 album containing 19 prints depicting Gus Hall during a visit to Romania, circa 1970s (Reel 20)
      Includes 3 prints depicting Nicolae Ceausescu.
  - Miscellaneous materials, 1935-1978
    Largely relating to the Communist Party of the United States of America and other communist parties.
    - Correspondence, notes, and reports
      - Folders 211-214. Unsorted (Reel 20)
      - Folder 215. 1959-1961 (Reel 20)
      - Folder 216. 1960-1961 (Reel 21)
      - Folder 217. 1961-1962 (Reel 21)
      - Folder 218. 1963 (Reel 21)
      - Folder 219. 1963-1971 (Reel 21)
      - Folder 220. 1964 (Reel 21)
      - Folder 221. 1964-1965 (Reel 21)
      - Folder 222. 1965 (Reel 21)
      - Folder 223. 1965-1967 (Reel 21)
      - Folder 224. 1966 (Reel 21)
      - Folder 225. 1971 (Reel 21)
      - Folder 226. 1972 (Reel 21)
      - Folder 227. 1973 (Reel 22)
      - Folder 228. 1974 (Reel 22)
      - Folder 229. 1975 (Reel 22)
      - Folder 230. 1976-1977 (Reel 22)
      - Folder 231. 1977 (Reel 22)
      - Folder 232. 1978 (Reel 22)
    - Notes taken by Morris Childs relating to his foreign travels
      - Folder 233. 1972 (Reel 22)
      - Folder 234. 1972-1974 (Reel 22)
    - Folders 235-236. Unsorted notebooks, undated (Reel 22)
    - Folders 237-242. Loose material, 1947-1970 (Reels 22, 22A, 23)
      Includes clippings, correspondence, directives, notes, and printed matter.
    - Folder 243. Discussion outline concerning decisions of the 7th World Congress of the Communist International, 1935 (Reel 23)
    - Notes
      Holograph and typescript notes made by Morris Childs, with some by others. Includes some address books, receipts, and printed matter.
      - Folders 244-246. Undated (Reel 23)
      - Folder 247. 1960s (Reel 23)
      - Folder 248. 1961-1965 (Reel 24)
      - Folder 249. 1968 (Reel 24)
      - Folder 250. 1970-1971 (Reel 24)
      - Folder 251. 1974 (Reel 24)
    - Covert operations materials, circa 1968
      - Folder 252. Catalog of listening devices (Reel 24)
      - Folder 253. Notes and lists (Reel 24)
      - Folder 254. Photographs of documents (Reel 24)
    - Folder 255. Reports and translations from the Soviet press, 1968-1976 (Reel 24)
    - Folder 256. Correspondence, notes, programs, and reports, 1964-1972 (Reel 25)
      Includes a photograph of a document by Gus Hall.
    - Folder 257. Clippings, correspondence, mailing addresses, minutes, and notes, 1969-1970 (Reel 25)
    - Folder 258. Campaign material, reports, resolutions, speeches, and survey, 1966-1968 (Reel 25)